Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to make it so that one of our character attacks,
Scranton or Scranton, will react with a damaged animation and their lost count and takes enough damage.
It will react with a death animation.
So if we head over to our Scranton blueprint.
And some free space, just right click and prevent any damage.
Now, this node will fire when our skeleton is damaged.
If you remember earlier, and I'll play a beep when we do our tag event, we do a line trace in front
of our player character and if it hits anything we call this apply damage node to the hit actor.
So when the actor is hit, it will call this event any damage node.
What we want to do is create a new variable and call it health.
I just make this variable type A float and go compile.
But now we just want to give us a help of three.
Then on event any damage you want to get the help the skeleton has.
I'm going to subtract it by whatever damage we took.
We don't want to tell the game that this is our new health.
So we just drag in our health and health and connect all the nodes here.
After this, I'm going to check to see if my health is less than or equal to zero to travel here and
look for Branch.
If this condition is false, that means my Scranton has more than zero health.
If that is true and they've just been damaged, we want to tell the game that we want the skeleton to
play the damaged animation.
So in order to do that, we can close this head into our animations folder and go to the skeleton animation
source.
I'm going to go add new and set new animation sequence.
Just rename this Scampton damaged.
Here under the animation data step, the skin tone damage flipbook.
So I call it scan to take care.
We also want to add a new animated sequence and call the scan to death.
And just like the scammed and death flipbook, we also want to add one more animation sequence and call
the scanned and dead body.
So after our skin tone dies, we just want to have an animation of a dead body.
So here are the animation data so that the scan and dead body.
Then if we head into our skeletons animation agreement.
We'll go to the new animation state machine and a jump net whenever our Scampton is damaged.
So if we just right click and forward jump and call this damaged.
Then over this node, we want to look for animation, see it, and just call this phantom damage.
If we don't click and hence out here we will right click and look for the play Skeleton damaged animation.
And just put this up here then if we connect from Scampton, damage to here.
So in order to transition from our scanned and damaged back to our normal idle start walking animation
step, if we head inside here just right click and look for time remaining Scampton damage.
So when there's less than 0.1 seconds of the animation remaining, we'll transition back to our normal
state.
So let us off here and look for less.
And here in the valley we're going to have 0.1 and just click this here.
We can just compile and we head back to our scans and BP.
Of course, I'm going to drag in my animation component from here.
We're going to look for get an instant.
And from here, we're going to drag off and jump to Node.
Connect this to false.
And here under jump name, I call mine damaged.
So I'm just going to hit and jump.
Name put damaged.
And I'm just gonna remove these line traces so that everything is a bit more clear to see.
I'll just go compile, save and close this and let it play.
And I hit what's going to do?
It will do the damage animation.
So I haven't really quickly.
So what I'm actually going to do is go to my accountant book and go to the take here.
And here I'm just going to take care.
I'm going to make the frames per second, like five.
Honestly make it six just a bit more slow and a bit more clear to see that we've hit the Scampton so
I can play.
That looked a bit better.
The next thing we're going to do is make it so if our skeleton takes enough damage, they will die.
So I go back to my animations.
I'm going to go to the animation.
Just right click, add another jump state and call this death.
Now, when we die, we're going to create a new animation stage and we'll call the first one die.
I'll head inside here and we just want to play our skeleton animation.
So we'll play Skeleton Death and hook this up here after we play our Skeleton Death animation.
We want to add another animation state and just call this dead body.
Here.
We just want to play our sentence that for the animation.
In order to transition from our diet to our dead body animation state, we're going to wait for our
Dalmatian to finish playing so we can just right click click for the time remaining skeleton depth.
And if this is less than.
0.1.
Well, transition to our dead body animation.
Then if I head back to my scans and beep and copy all these notes, paste them here, and this time
under jump name, I called mine.
Death.
Yeah, I call it death.
So here, I'm going to have death.
And I'm just going to go compile and we can now test this out.
So go play.
If I hit my Scantron three times, I should die.
One, two, three.
Alone.
Third one.
It died.
Nice.
So after I cut my Scantron, we can see its body is still moving and it's kind of blocking me.
So we're going to do a couple of things.
When Oscar Nintendo's.
The first thing I'm going to do is just tell the game that it's dead.
So I'm gonna create an example and I'll call it is dead.
I'll make this babble type a float, sorry, a boolean and just go compile.
Then when I scan, ten is dead, I'm just going to drag in this babble and that will set is dead.
I'm just going to leave it checked.
Then on handle movement.
I have a branch.
And the condition of the branch it's going to be is dead.
And we just want to break from truth.
Only if Scranton is not dead.
We're going to continue adding movement info.
Across concerns that just so that we can overlap it and look past it, we're going to drug in its capsule
component and just drag up here and it will set collision by profile name.
And under inclusion or just like this capsule collision.
Right now it's set to --.
We're going to set to overlap only --.
So I'll play a character.
Also has a -- collection.
And by setting it to overlap, any -- or player character will be able to walk over the dead body
of our scandal.
So under here, I'm going to change the collision profile name to overlap only or make sure this is
spelt correctly, otherwise it won't work.
After this, I'm going to have a delay.
Of a 3 seconds.
And then I'm going to destroy this actor.
Look for the Detroit actor, and this will just destroy it.
It's never going to compile close this and go play.
I hit my scan two, three times.
One, two, three.
It will die and just stop moving.
And after 3 seconds, it should be destroyed.
Nice.
So we've made it so we can damage our scanner.
Think.
Still look a bit off when I attack my Scampton.
So in the next lecture, we're going to polish it up a bit.